Leon Chan | Software Engineer | Database Developer

I am a software engineer who is constantly inspired by the continuous innovation and growth in the tech industry. My experience with tutoring and in marketing has helped me build skills in communication, teamwork, and creative problem solving which I implement as a software developer to build engaging and accessible websites. As a teammate, I am equally determined and cheerful- driven to achieve our goal but also determined to enjoy the process!

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON,
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Deployment: Heroku, Netlify Other: JSON, API
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Mongoose, Flask

PROJECTS

Duck-UI-Pattern | A social media web application where users can select and view images

- Utilized Model to create a format, With boxes containing images a user can click to reveal information.
- Built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Digimon-react-API-UI-pattern | Single Page Web Application where users can click through different characters

- Built a website where users can click through different characters from the popular show.
- Used CSS, front-end, back-end, Postman, and pulled from an API.
- Deployed in Netlify.

<u>Seven-Wonders</u> | A front-end website where users can learned the magnificent architectures build millenniums ago.

Built with HTML, CSS, Front-end, and React.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Apprentice | General Assembly | New York, NY

2/2022 - 5/2022

- Built competencies in Front-end, Back-end programming in a project based learning environment where I wrote code with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and more.
- Creatively designed and programmed full stack web applications while collaborating with other developers, and working independently.
- Performed trouble shooting, automation, front end integrations, and deployments during independent and peer coding exercises.

Program/Learning/Technical Aide | Research Foundation of CUNY | New York, NY

10/2016 – Present

- Help students understand the concept of Chinese in writing, speaking, listening and reading.
- Exam preparation for students.

Social Media Marketing Intern | SPAtlight Marketing | Remote

1/2021 - 5/2021

- Designed and created posts and stories for clinic's Instagram page while utilizing Canva
- Wrote engaging captions for the posts to increase interactions on the page and bring in additional business to the spa.
- Demonstrated understanding of cosmetic terminology in social media captions and conducting research to stay informed on industry trends.

Volunteer | Hester Street | New York, NY

1/2012 - 1/2017

- Installed lantern along Grand Street for Chinese New Year celebration.
- Rebuilt and decorated the water park at Pier 42 during the summer session.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, *Software Engineering Immersive* / New York, NY 5/2022

2/2022 -